Katelin Frederick

Toledo, OH

517-902-2738

k.frederick94@gmail.com

Summary

I am a full-stack web developer with over 5 years of experience. I specialize in tools including React.js, Next.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, and AWS resources such as S3, Lambda, and DynamoDB. I have worked on agile teams building serverless web applications consisting of user forms and admin dashboards hosted using AWS.

I thoroughly enjoy learning new processes and tools to keep up with industry standards and grow my skill set. In addition to coding, I enjoy helping other developers learn and grow in their careers. I have strong communication, documentation, analytical, and critical thinking skills.

- Skills: JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Git, HTML, CSS, Python
- AWS: DynamoDB, Lambda, S3, CloudWatch, API Gateway, Secrets Manager, Cognito
- Agile: JIRA, Bitbucket, GitHub, Agile Planning, Agile Team Practices, Scrum

Relevant Experience

Accenture Federal Services

Lead Developer 04/2023 - Present

- Led an agile team of four developers, fostering a collaborative and productive work environment.
 Supported team members by providing technical guidance and ensuring alignment with project goals.
- Oversaw the development and enhancement of a comprehensive suite of applications allowing
 users to upload documents digitally with ease and efficiency. The suite had over 1 million
 submissions in 2024 and saved over 4 million pages of paper.
- Developed and enhanced accompanying suite of admin applications allowing over 20,000 users to manage submissions, streamlining internal workflows and reducing processing times.
- Directed the strategic migration of the codebase from JavaScript to TypeScript, significantly
 enhancing error handling and code maintainability, leading to a more robust and scalable
 application architecture.
- Designed, implemented, and consumed RESTful APIs for seamless data exchange between administrative and public applications, ensuring data consistency and integrity across different platforms.
- Provided guidance and mentorship to junior and mid-level developers, fostering a collaborative and growth-oriented environment. Conducted code reviews, shared best practices, provided performance feedback, and supported career development.
- Delegated tickets and tasks to team members, ensuring work was distributed according to individual strengths and project requirements.
- Conducted comprehensive and interactive application demonstrations for clients, highlighting key features, functionalities, and benefits of developed solutions.

Full-Stack Engineer 03/2021 - 03/2023

 Designed, built, and implemented applications based on business requirements and design wireframes.

- Worked closely with design teams to meet and surpass user experience standards. Ensured visual
 design and user interface were intuitive, accessible, and aligned with user needs.
- Implemented serverless architecture using Serverless Framework and AWS resources, including Lambda, API Gateway, S3, and DynamoDB. This approach increased application scalability, reduced operational overhead, and optimized cost-efficiency.
- Collaborated with testing teams to troubleshoot and resolve defects in a timely manner. Conducted
 root cause analysis and implemented effective solutions ensuring stability and reliability of
 applications.
- Created and maintained comprehensive documentation, including technical specifications, API documentation, user guides, and troubleshooting manuals.

Application Developer

07/2019 - 02/2021

- Worked as a developer re-writing several Java Spring Boot applications with React and Next.js, delivering a modern user interface with improved user experience, application performance, and maintainability.
- Collaborated closely with design teams ensuring applications adhered to UI/UX standards, for consistent and seamless user experience. Participated in design discussions to align technical implementation with design goals.
- Implemented multilingual functionality into applications, enabling users to view and interact with applications in seven different languages. This enhancement expanded the user base and improved accessibility for non-English speaking users.
- Created application interfaces from wireframes provided by design teams, ensuring accurate translation of design concepts into functional and visually appealing user interfaces.
- Worked with the 508 testing team to ensure applications met accessibility standards.
- Actively participated in agile ceremonies, activities, and planning, including daily stand-ups, sprint reviews, retrospectives, and sprint planning sessions. Contributed to team discussions and collaborative problem-solving to achieve project goals.

Education

Associate's degree in fine arts, Jackson College